# Derick A. Gross

New York, NY | derick.gross@gmail.com | derickgross.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

I am an AWS Certified Solutions Architect and software engineer in New York City, with several years experience architecting and building back-end solutions using cloud technologies. In my devops and product engineering role with Ridgeline's Market Data team, I build complex integrations with external vendors, optimize automated CI/CD and testing processes, and monitor performance and availability of critical subsystems.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## DevOps and Product Engineer, Ridgeline 8/2020-present

- Integrated with external vendors to ingest updates to securities, market capitalizations, corporate actions, etc., providing required data feeds for 83% of new customers
- Collaborated cross-team with portfolio accounting on critical API and workflow enhancements that contributed to 1000x performance increase in V2 system
- Eliminated 25% of fixed costs for pipeline testing environments by identifying and removing environments where fixed cost exceeded variable cost with no impact on code velocity
- Implemented site reliability solutions using Datadog monitors integrated with Slack channels and messaging, improving response rate to failures from 3 hours to 7 minutes
- Built reusable relational subquery and query components to replace in-memory data processing, boosting performance  $\sim 9x$
- Advocated for regular and formal technical design reviews to increase knowledge sharing, decrease re-work, and empower faster and more thoughtful code review
- Designed devops mentoring program to formalize knowledge sharing

## Co-Creator and Software Engineer, Apex 1/2020-4/2020 apex-api-proxy.github.io/

- Designed solution architecture, relational table schema, middleware logic.
- Built admin user interface (React) and API (Node/Express)

## Instructor Lead - Software Engineering, General Assembly 3/2019-6/2019

• Principles of OOP, HTML/CSS/JS, REST APIs, SQL, database design, Git, DS&A

## Software Developer, True Earth Health Products 11/2016-3/2019

• Full stack, database and cloud development

Software Developer, Unytus 5/2016-10/2016

#### SKILLS and TECHNOLOGIES

AWS, Python, Azure, Docker, JavaScript/Node.js/Typescript, .NET Core, Ruby/Rails, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Redis, SSMS, Git/Github, REST APIs, React/Redux, Jira

# **EDUCATION and CERTIFICATION**

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect (Associate) December 2021
- Launch School mastery-based software development (2016 2017, 2019 2020)
- Columbia University Chemical Engineering (1999-2004, 20 credits remaining)